homeswapper.co.uk 2016-11-19

# HomeSwapper | Tenant Privacy Policy

  1. ## Introduction

Housing Partners Limited ("we" or "us") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This privacy policy (together with our terms of use www.homeswapper.co.uk/Terms and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting www.homeswapper.co.uk (the "site") and/or making use of our products/services you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this privacy policy. 

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the "Act"), the data controller is Housing Partners Limited of Whittington Hall, Whittington Road, Worcester, Worcestershire, WR5 2RY, England, UK (company number 04667857). 

  2. ## Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

    * **Information you give us.**  
You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our site, by registering with us or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our service, search for a product and when you report a problem with our site and/or products or services. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information, personal description and photograph, and other personal data (including sensitive personal data) that you provide us. 

    * **Information we collect about you.**  
We may also collect, and our third party providers of advertisements and content may collect, the following information: 

      * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; 

      * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service team. 

    * **Information we receive from other sources.**  
We may receive information about you: 

      * if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide; 

      * from third parties, including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, data processing and provision companies, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies; 

      * specifically from landlords. 

    * **Aggregated data and statistics.**  
We may use aggregate data and statistics for the purpose of monitoring the site usage in order to help us develop the site and our services. We may provide such aggregated data to third parties for adverting or other purposes. The statistics will not include information that can be used to identify any individual. 

  3. ## Cookies

Our site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site and also allows us to improve our site. 

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

We use the following cookies: 

**Strictly necessary cookies.**  
These are cookies that are required for the operation of our site. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our site. 

    * **Analytical/performance cookies.**  
They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our site when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our site works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily. 

    * **Functionality cookies.**  
These are used to recognise you when you return to our site. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region). 

    * **Targeting cookies.**  
These cookies record your visit to our site, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our site and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose. 

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site. 

For more information about cookies, including how to change your browser settings and find and delete cookies on your hard drive, please visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

To opt-out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

  4. ## Uses made of the information

In general, we process your personal data:

    * for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy;

    * for additional purposes that you would reasonably anticipate or that we state (and for which, if necessary, you consent) when we collect your personal data;

    * where necessary, for our other legitimate interests; 

    * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us; and

    * to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us.

    * **Information you give to us.**  
We will use this information: 

      * to manage your account and contract with us;

      * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;

      * to provide you with information about other products and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;

      * to notify you about changes to our products and services;

      * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 

    * **Information we collect about you.**  
We collect the following information from you: your name; gender; date of birth; address; email; mobile number; telephone number; level of housing related benefit; number of bedrooms; number of occupants; type of tenancy; council tax level; details of the type of house required; details of the location in which you want to live and the new address in the event of a successful home swap. We will use this information: 

We will use this information: 

      * to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;

      * to improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; 

      * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;

      * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;

      * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;

      * to provide you and third parties with our products and services;

      * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about goods or services that may interest you or them.

    * **Information we receive from other sources.**  
We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive). 

    * **Marketing Communications.**  
We may use information you provide us to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about products or services we feel may interest you in the following manner. 

      * You give us your consent to receive marketing information from us about our products and services we believe will be of interest to you that are similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you by choosing not to opt-out on your registration form.

      * You give us your consent to receiving marketing information from third parties about their products and services by choosing to opt-in on your registration form

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data. You can change your mind and remove or add your consent at any time by choosing to "unsubscribe" from mailings on receipt of such material, or you may notify us that you no longer wish to receive such material by contacting us our address at the top of this page or [tenants@homeswapper.co.uk](mailto:tenants@homeswapper.co.uk). 

We will endeavour to comply with your request as soon as we are reasonably able to do so. If your information has been passed to third parties with your consent you may need to contact them if you change your mind in relation to their continued use of your information. Please also note that the opt-ins and opt-outs on this site (unless specifically stated otherwise) cover all means of communicating with you, including by email, post, phone, SMS text message and other electronic means. When you choose to opt-in or opt-out through the site, this opt-in or opt-out will only apply to the information stored about you on this site's databases. If you have provided information to us through another channel, the use of that information will not be affected by the opt-ins or opt-outs you select on the site. 

  5. ## Disclosure of your information

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may share your information with selected third parties including:

    * Landlords, to enable a landlord to find you the best available housing option with the best possible support, and in order to add certain information to our data profiling services.

    * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you, including housing associations, councils, landlords and any other third parties that we consider may be able to assist you in finding housing opportunities.

    * Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. 

    * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site. 

    * Credit reference agencies for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of us entering into a contract with you.

    * Lenders for the purposes of granting credit, preventing fraud and/or tracing account holders.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

    * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

    * If Housing Partners Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

    * If we are under a duty to disclose (including, without limitation, to local authorities, police or other statutory bodies) or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use or terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

  6. ## Where and how we store your personal data

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access, including those set out below.

    * Our security procedures include those relating to storage, access and disclosure of your personal data. If you are a registrant of our services your identity shall be confirmed by reference to unique information such as a user name and password. The user name and password shall enable you to use the services. It is your responsibility to keep your user name and password confidential.

    * With the exception of housing associations, councils, landlords and all other third parties whom we consider may assist you in finding housing opportunities all other third parties with whom your details will be shared shall not be provided with the user name or password you have provided.

    * All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers and we take all reasonable steps to ensure, and require all third parties to whom your personal data is disclosed, to treat your personal information as fully confidential and to fully comply with the Act.

  7. ## Your rights

If any of the personal data that you have provided to us changes, for example if your contact details change, please update your registration directly via the site.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

  8. ## Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

  9. ## Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

  10. ## Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to: Housing Partners Limited of Whittington Hall, Whittington Road, Worcester, Worcestershire, WR5 2RY, England, UK.
